I wish I could
win the lottery.
That girl's shoes
are cute.
Why won't she text me back?
I need a boyfriend.
I ate too much yesterday.
Ooh, she really does like me.
I'm so sleepy.
I think my back tooth
is hurting.
Hey, don't step on my feet.
Aw, I wish I had
my license.
I'm staying
home tomorrow.
Aww, I wish I was more popular.
All right, my horoscope says I'll have
a great day. Ah, that boy looks cool!
I'm able to read people's minds.
Or more precisely,
I hear what they're thinking
as though they were telling a story.
Everything people want
to know is written in my blog.
I'm going to eat my fill of meat today!
I've named this power "Monologue."
But I haven't told anyone. If people
found out, I'd be ostracized by them.
Because no one would be comfortable
with having someone else
knowing what they're thinking.
That's why I lied and told
the others that my dumb parlor trick
of being able to stick one-yen coins
to my forehead was my power.
I haven't revealed this power to anyone.
No one else has found out about it yet,
nor does anyone even suspect it.
I have total confidence in it.
I mean, after all,
I know what everyone else is thinking!
Maybe I got here a little too early.
Maybe that was a bit too quick.
But now, I'll get a little more time.
After we left, we went
around to a few other worlds,
and successfully finished
Ms. Aki's summer camp.
We had a bit of a bumpy road,
but we must have completed what
she called her "compulsory education."
We were all dismissed,
and at the end, we were given
the rank of Private 5th Class,
and an invitation to the battlefield.
I no longer had any reason to stay
with him, and was terribly bummed out.
After all, I really like Asakaze.
Our being able to finish our camp today
is the result of Ms. Aki's
intensive instruction and guidance.
As was our rubbing elbows with
friends with whom we can work hard.
The bonds we have fostered here
will never be outdone...
...and are precious treasures.
I've ended up being nobody at all, huh?
We will carry these experiences
we gained at summer camp
The only thing I can boast over the others
is my perfect attendance award.
with us for the rest of our lives,
and always embrace this camaraderie.
What's going to become of me now?
You've been recognized by God, right?
You're in the elite course.
You really are awesome, Asakaze.
We're proud to have been
in the same class as you!
It's no big deal.
Watching everyone
buttering me up like this,
it feels good, but at the same time,
disconcerting somehow.
The simpleton thinks he's so hot.
Fall on your face, you idiot!
These guys aren't being
entirely truthful, are they?
They're just saying what
would sound nice to anyone, right?
But that's okay. I'm not like you guys.
I don't mean apples and oranges, either;
more like the toilet bowl and its turds.
He's on another roll today.
This is the real Asakaze,
the one that only I know. His story is...
Wh-What did you think of my speech?
Oh, it was very nice.
Y-You think so? I'm not
very good at these things...
Aw, she's so cute today. Pretty soon,
we won't see each other anymore.
Come on, declare your feelings for her!
Oh, but I'm too afraid.
I should ask her out first—
Huh?
I couldn't bear to watch that.
But I'm no different than Kaga.
Somehow, he finds me off-putting.
What's up?
Oh...
...you've been in touch
with Nozomi recently, right?
I mean, it's not like
I'm interested in her, or anything.
What is she doing right now?
I sure miss her.
She can't even do anything, but I'll
bet she's still acting high and mighty.
Asakaze is in love with Nozomi.
Ever since we first went adrift.
She seems fine.
Apparently, she's on Hateno Island
with Nagara and the others.
She's still there?
Nagara! That scum.
It's because of what he said that...
Oh, hey, I need a favor from you.
Would you help me with my work?
I was just looking for a chore girl.
She's one of those types. I've never
seen anyone ask her to help them.
When she hears she can be helpful to
someone, she'll be delighted easily.
I was just wondering what path to
take next. Are you sure I can help you?
She must really like me. Aw, but
she's not the one I want to attract.
You don't have to answer right away.
Give it some thought.
Mm-hmm, thanks.
He's stubborn, and selfish,
and a little ill-natured.
Strange, isn't it? It stings
a little every time I talk to him.
Even so, I like Asakaze.
Ever since we first went adrift.
I knew it.
This isn't your power at all.
It's just the way it is.
This is what you get for
being pushy, you ugly gorilla.
I'm the chosen one here.
Look down on me all this time, will you?
I won't have anyone not doing what I say!
Hey now, this is a super-funny face
you're making, huh?
Get lost, get lost! And don't
ever enter my sight again!
H-How mean...
Why is she with Nagara, though?
I'm the one who's protecting everybody.
Nozomi, look at me.
I'm not the same person I was before.
This is so awesome.
I'm sure she'll be thrilled
if I show this to her.
Nozomi!
Leave her to herself.
I just want to keep Nozomi safe.
She's just going to keep
slowing everyone else down.
Do you really mean that?
This way, Nozomi will reevaluate me,
and why she turned me down.
She doesn't know the real me, that's all.
It would be... better if
she didn't go with you.
Asakaze's unrequited love
must have ended in heartbreak.
I see him being an outcast from
the world someday, becoming isolated,
and then finally landing at my feet.
I fantasize about that day.
But I know that Asakaze would never
come to me, because he thinks I'm ugly.
Yeah. Not unless the world changes.
That's something I know
better than anyone.
So if I can at least...
Ms. Aki's boobs...
She's taking Asakaze down the wrong path.
She's taking Asakaze down the
wrong path
She doesn't think of Asakaze as anything.
She's only interested in his power.
Aw, this is such a pain.
He should get away
from her, fast! For sure!
There is currently someone who
jeopardizes the existence of this world.
It is War.
I need you to put a stop to War.
I want you to kill him.
This is something that no one else
has ever been able to accomplish.
You're going to create
"death" in this world.
I know you can do it.
Because we are static people,
we can't move forward any farther.
We all have nothing to do,
nor anything we can do.
We don't know where the trains are going,
what roles we've been given,
or even who our enemies
are supposed to be.
All we do have here is
a vague sense of insecurity.
We're not supposed to die, though.
But Asakaze thinks that
he can change the world.
He's obsessed with
"a great task that only I can do."
And I'm not able to change Asakaze.
Each of the three cats has
their own role that they play.
Tora places the orders,
Gen transports them,
and Sakura copies the things
being brought from your own world.
Including living things.
Okay, Sakura, make another me!
Hey, what's the matter? Make another—
The cats must have
their own sense of ethics.
They know that if they
use their powers recklessly,
they will create unnecessary tragedy.
Okay, so, does this mean that she is
the one behind our castaway copies?
Yeah, most likely. But just as with
Nagara's creating worlds,
she was only unconsciously involved
in the phenomenon happening.
Huh? Then what about you, Mizuho?
What have you been doing all this time?
Who, me?
Hmm... What have
I been doing all this time?
Rajdhani didn't take into
account the cats' feelings.
Maybe that's why he didn't pick up
on Mizuho's own personal potential.
We're being held captive by a drift
that has already happened.
Mizuho's power...
...may have something to do
with our being in stasis.
If you had known about this at the time,
the outcome might have
turned out differently.
I think I might go together with them.
I've been curious about something.
I thought you hated smartphones.
Mm-hmm, yeah, I used to.
Nozomi was the only one...
...who treated the others
without any deceit.
I follow my heart.
It's what I believe, so it's what I do.
Maybe Nozomi can get Asakaze to...
Long time no see.
Huh? Been waiting long?
Mm-mm.
Oh, they're huge.
What are you doing here, Nozomi?
Is it wrong if I am?
You're disrupting my work.
Maybe so, but Nozomi is here now.
Where did you go with Ms. Aki?
We're going to go put down
a bad guy to ensure world peace.
You really are amazing, Asakaze.
Say, would you bring us along with you
when you put down this bad guy?
Why?
Well, I'd like to see you in action.
Nozomi, you would, too, right?
Well, I don't really...
You would, too, right?
It would be dangerous for you.
After all, the one
I'm taking down is "War."
War...?
So this is "War," is it?
That horrible woman...
This guy is War?
What's up with him?
Are you all right?
This guy is empty.
I know...
Huh?
Dinner...
...should about be ready, right?
Oh, right.
What's the matter? Did something happen?
You've been acting strange
ever since the station.
You know what? I...
How about a short break?
This sure is a dull world.
Where could War be?
What are you going to do
when you find War?
Huh? Why do you ask?
Are you going to kill him
because he's War?
There is no police or military force here.
Someone has to do it. That someone is me.
You don't even know what War is.
What's the big idea, creating death?
You think you've become God or something?
How do you even know about that?
Because that girl can see
right through all of us.
She has the power to
read other people's minds.
Is that true?
You know everything? How I feel?
What I'm thinking right now?
I'm sorry.
Those two...
What, were they laughing at me?!
There, there.
When I adjust the scale,
I can hear her voice quite well.
Using my power relativistically, that is.
All right, finished.
Those are more power holdovers.
Mm-hmm, I got them from Nagara.
These are just perfect for me.
This gorge really does seem like
a deep wound cut into the world, huh?
Mm-hmm. It coincides with
what Yamabiko said about War, too.
But is this War even taking place?
I was wondering that, too.
At the train station,
I overheard a lot of voices,
but none of them knew anything about War.
I don't have to use any powers
to know what's in your mind.
Go ahead and mock me.
Who do you think made it
possible for you to even be here?
That's true even now.
You could at least...
Do you want me to tell you
why I turned you down?
It's because I can't respect you.
That's why I can't go out with you.
Everyone else, including God,
acknowledges me.
It's not about everyone else. It's about
what you decided you were worth.
I'm leaving. Even if I am dead,
I can accept my own fate.
I could never be as strong as you are.
I couldn't acknowledge who I was,
other than the power I was given.
I could never be like you.
Maybe that's why I kept pursuing you.
But then, that ends today.
Okay, got it. Then this is goodbye.
Nozomi really was the only one
who could change Asakaze.
This time, I'll be the one
to show you the light.
Okay, let's put an end to this "War."
You're the only one who
can conquer This World.
I'll admit that.
You were chosen by This World.
There's nothing but a huge
wound remaining here now.
He's spent too much time here.
Let's put a stop to it already.
Nozomi!
Good grief.
You can't even peer that
deeply into your own heart.
Hey, Asakaze!
Why didn't I...?
The fruit of a
spontaneously-occurring power...
Don't you think it's beautiful?
I thought I knew the real Asakaze.
But I was wrong.
The right chicken is the one you ordered,
and the left one is the one I asked for.
Are we really doing this?
No, we can't!
Mizuho didn't want to see anyone die.
Let's have oyako donburi tonight.
The least we can do is eat her.